and something fun. This is the show that helps you build systems so your business
doesn't depend on you. Hopefully this week's curation will get you thinking about
your own systems before you close your laptop for the weekend. I'm your host, Joe
Casabona, and here's what's on my mind. For July 24th, 2026,
the thing that's on my mind is the simplicity of yellow legal pads. I am a man who
has spent 30 to $40 on a notebook, over $100 on leather bound disc books with refillable
pages, and
more than I'd like to admit on fountain pens.
But over the weekend, I rediscovered yellow legal pads. I needed a notebook and grabbed
whatever I found in the first draw I was near,
and I forgot how satisfying it is to use a yellow legal pad. The amount of space
worried about how I'm using it or if I'm using it for the right thing.
I stopped using yellow legal pads because most don't accommodate fountain pens. And
I, I like using fountain pens. My complicated approach,
for the past week, I've only used my yellow legal pad and it's been delightful. I'm
taking a couple of them on vacation with me next week,
and I still love fancy notebooks, but in my fancy notebook phase, I fell into the
trap of feeling like the notebooks I bought needed to be used for something important,
so it added friction to my process. Every time I needed to do something, I would
think, is this the notebook I really want to burn on this random thing?
this is a little much, this is a little extra. Uh, yeah, it absolutely is. But I
do love a good notebook. I have a fountain pen collection
and I love using them, and I still have that paper. I still have those notebooks
and I will still use those notebooks. But
for everyday writing for scribbling down whatever I'm thinking for bringing stuff
with me when I want to think without a screen, the yellow legal pad is the way to
go. It is simple
and you don't have to think about it. And that's really the hallmark of a good system,
right? Reducing the amount of friction between you and the task you're trying to
accomplish.
Now, I do happen to like thicker paper in general, so I do recommend the AMPA gold
fiber legal pads.
They're a little bit more expensive than,
but that's okay. I mean, it's a, a long way from
and it's about
how she discovered her biography on Amazon,
but it's not something that she authorized or was even contacted or talked to about.
No, the book had been totally generated by ai, and she's not the only victim of someone
trying to profit off of her story in just the laziest way possible.
writing,
and she even interviews an AI
author.
Would you believe that most reviews of these AI books, especially from this AI author,
I
for us more than most people, right? I, I constantly talk about how terrible and
toxic and destructive it is, and when someone tells me they are using it to write
for them, I am not shy about telling them how terrible it is.
letting AI take a thought you have and turn it into a series of generic soulless,
statistically likely sentences, isn't it? And if you are sitting there going, well,
not.
It is that it's a robot, not a writer.
And
I, I talk about this because I want
solopreneurs to spend their time
wisely
to destroy the trust that your clients, your customers, the people you partner with
have in you
in an age where you can create anything from nothing
with a few sentences to a word calculator.
The thing that will last is trust and human connection.
And you will not get that
by telling people you are too lazy to write your own thoughts down.
You will not get that by trying to swindle people out of even $10 for a book you
are claiming to write that you didn't write or research or review,
you will not get that.
It is a tool that is great for certain tasks
and not for craft.
That is and will always lie with us.
Okay,
Uh, I kind of feel like I need a drink now, which is good because for something fun,
I am recommending a piece by Peter Suman called Want to Feel Rich, drink a Pineapple
Cocktail. I enjoy trying my hand at interesting cocktails. I'm not really much of
a drinker. I like the craft
of cocktails, understanding the ingredients and how the flavors come together to
I like the craft part of it. And my favorite cocktail website
has been doing a fantastic series on summery drinks.
As I prepare for the beach,
I am checking the most interesting sounding recipes and bringing some ingredients
along with me to make cocktails for my wife and her family.
I am excited to try a pineapple cocktail. I just had like a pineapple sour
beer the other day, and it was just delightfully, delightfully refreshing.
As an aside, I also use Peter Suter Man's Eggnog recipe or on Christmas, and it is
always a huge hit. I mix it exactly the way he says to mix it, and then I age it
for two to three weeks.
So I'll usually make it like right after Thanksgiving
it's really good.
Okay? And for the automation of the week, I wanna talk about episode artwork generation
for the Friday wrap up. You'll know this if you are a listening and a podcast player
that supports this, but
I have custom episode artwork that is just the Friday wrap up logo with the current
date,
underneath it. So,
in something a bit meta, I wanna talk about a new action I added for my Friday wrap
up AI skill,
which helps me generate the assets for
these episodes and newsletters. And again, this is going back to the AI is for task
not craft.
So among other things, Claude has a Canva connector, and when I run the Friday wrap
skill, it will figure out the next Friday. This includes
Fridays on the day the skill is run, which is usually the case. I record this early
on Friday morning, so I can release it by mid Friday morning,
and then it will send that date to Canva, grab my Friday wrap up artwork template,
and change the text on the image to the current date
when I was prompted by the upload custom artwork field
in my podcast host. So
this is something that I would forget to do, and then it would, you know, just prolong
the process a few extra minutes.
But now it's done for me automatically. And since this is done,
while the video for this episode is rendering, it's a huge time saver for me. It
means all the assets are done at the same time as I'm prepping for them to publish
or as I'm prepping them for publish, I guess I should say. So
this is such a fun one. I'm definitely going to explore
using Canva for stuff like this because the main episodes are also just like text
or sometimes a headshot, and my VA is doing that right now, but if I could take this
task off my VA's plate,
I can free her up for other more important work that requires human discernment and
not just filling in fields in an image template. So really excited about this automation
and until next time, I hope you find some space in your weekend.